John A. Holmes Papers MS007
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
- Poetry, 1922 -- 1962; 1940 -- 1961; MS007.001; 7.25 Linear Feet; 1 Audiovisual Object(s)
  - Thoughts of a man asleep, MS007.001.001.00145; Holmes, John (Box 1)
  - To poets: advice, MS007.001.001.00146; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 054.
  - Amaze, MS007.001.001.00147; Holmes, John (Box 1)
  - The reverent lover, MS007.001.001.00148; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 054. duplicate in 9:073
  - A quotation, MS007.001.001.00149; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 055. Annotated
  - The unseen lady, MS007.001.001.00150; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 055.
  - My bookshelf, MS007.001.001.00151; Holmes, John (Box 1)
  - Thoughts at night, MS007.001.001.00152; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 056.
  - Suspicion, MS007.001.001.00153; Holmes, John (Box 1)
  - Fall in Massachusetts, MS007.001.001.00154; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 056. Revision in 10:034, p. 98 is handwritten. revision in 10:034, p. 98
  - Music, MS007.001.001.00155; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 057.
  - America, MS007.001.001.00156; Holmes, John (Box 1)
  - I remember, MS007.001.001.00157; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 058.
  - Lines to an old dish, MS007.001.001.00158; Holmes, John (Box 1)
  - Window glass, MS007.001.001.00159; Holmes, John (Box 1)
  - Sonnet, MS007.001.001.00160; Holmes, John (Box 1)
  - At a funeral, MS007.001.001.00161; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 059.
  - Disillusionment, MS007.001.001.00162; Holmes, John (Box 1)
  - The seekers, 1923-10-01; MS007.001.001.00163; Holmes, John (Box 1)
  - Il Penseroso (R.S.), 1923-10-01; MS007.001.001.00164; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 059. revision in 8:014
  - Effect of praise, MS007.001.001.00165; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 060.
  - When hearts are young, MS007.001.001.00166; Holmes, John (Box 1)
  - The clean winds, MS007.001.001.00167; Holmes, John (Box 1)
  - The lover serenades, 1923-10-21; MS007.001.001.00168; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 061. Annotated
  - The little street, MS007.001.001.00169; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 062. revision in 9:040
  - Laughter, MS007.001.001.00170; Holmes, John (Box 1)
  - To one gone, MS007.001.001.00171; Holmes, John (Box 1)
  - The dancers, MS007.001.001.00172; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 062.
  - A poet burns some poems, MS007.001.001.00173; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 063.
  - Writing, MS007.001.001.00174; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 064. revision in 7:116
  - Walking in the rain, MS007.001.001.00175; Holmes, John (Box 1)
  - A sacrifice to the sun, MS007.001.001.00176; Holmes, John (Box 1)
  - To my cousin, H.R.B., 1923-11-15; MS007.001.001.00177; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 065. Duplicate in 8:098 is dated November 15, 1923. duplicate in 8:098
  - The boat, 1923-11-15; MS007.001.001.00178; Holmes, John (Box 1)
  - Poem, 1923-11-15; MS007.001.001.00179; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 065. Revision in 8:098 is dated November 15, 1923. revision in 8:098
  - Overture, 1923-11-18; MS007.001.001.00180; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 066. Revision in 9:073 is annotated. revision in 9:073
  - Snow, 1923-11-18; MS007.001.001.00181; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 066.
  - Hope, 1923-11-18; MS007.001.001.00182; Holmes, John (Box 1)
  - A song for you, 1923-11-18; MS007.001.001.00183; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 066. Poem crossed out duplicate in 1:75
  - Window dreaming, 1923-06-02; MS007.001.001.00184; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 067.
  - Rain the morning after, 1923-06-02; MS007.001.001.00185; Holmes, John (Box 1)
  - A man's club, 1923-06-02; MS007.001.001.00186; Holmes, John (Box 1)
  - From the tower, 1923-06-02; MS007.001.001.00187; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 067. Duplicate in 8:092 is handwritten. duplicate in 8:092
  - Fairies by night, MS007.001.001.00188; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 068.
  - The young poet, MS007.001.001.00189; Holmes, John (Box 1)
  - Rain, 1923-10-01; MS007.001.001.00190; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 069. Revision in 9:044 is handwritten. revision in 9:044
  - Say good night, 1923-10-01; MS007.001.001.00191; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 069.
  - The thought of you, 1923; MS007.001.001.00192; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 069. revision in 6:015
  - A youth, 1923-10-01; MS007.001.001.00193; Holmes, John (Box 1)
  - Nocturne, MS007.001.001.00194; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 070.
  - Courage, MS007.001.001.00195; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 071.
  - Cinquain, MS007.001.001.00196; Holmes, John (Box 1)
  - Circles, MS007.001.001.00197; Holmes, John (Box 1)
  - The cabin boy climbs the crow's nest, MS007.001.001.00198; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 073.
  - On going to bed, MS007.001.001.00199; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 074. Revision in 9:071 is handwritten. revision in 9:071
  - Three roads, MS007.001.001.00200; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 074.
  - 1492, MS007.001.001.00201; Holmes, John (Box 1)
  - October, MS007.001.001.00202; Holmes, John (Box 1)
  - Pan, MS007.001.001.00203; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 075.
  - Soldiers, MS007.001.001.00204; Holmes, John (Box 1)
  - To a girl who has black eyes, MS007.001.001.00205; Holmes, John (Box 1)
  - The hilly place, MS007.001.001.00206; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 076.
  - The call, MS007.001.001.00207; Holmes, John (Box 1)
  - Lines, MS007.001.001.00208; Holmes, John (Box 1)
  - The poet's prayer, MS007.001.001.00209; Holmes, John (Box 1)
  - Futility, MS007.001.001.00210; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 077.
  - The priest, MS007.001.001.00211; Holmes, John (Box 1)
  - Meditation, MS007.001.001.00212; Holmes, John (Box 1)
  - Two songs, MS007.001.001.00213; Holmes, John (Box 1)
  - Cappricco, MS007.001.001.00214; Holmes, John (Box 1)
  - Stars, 1923-06-25; MS007.001.001.00215; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 078.
  - Westward ho!, 1923-06-25; MS007.001.001.00216; Holmes, John (Box 1)
  - Rain, MS007.001.001.00217; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 079.
  - A man remembers suddenly, MS007.001.001.00218; Holmes, John (Box 1)
  - At the museum, MS007.001.001.00219; Holmes, John (Box 1)
  - Morning in the forest, MS007.001.001.00220; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 080.
  - A charm to keep away evil, MS007.001.001.00221; Holmes, John (Box 1)
  - The lover grows older, MS007.001.001.00222; Holmes, John (Box 1)
  - An apology, MS007.001.001.00223; Holmes, John (Box 1)
  - An old legend retold on the occasion of a certain death, MS007.001.001.00224; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 081.
  - Aftermath, MS007.001.001.00225; Holmes, John (Box 1)
  - Old words, MS007.001.001.00226; Holmes, John (Box 1)
  - Raw material, MS007.001.001.00227; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 082.
  - Masks, MS007.001.001.00228; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 083.
  - The grace of god, 1923-10-01; MS007.001.001.00229; Holmes, John (Box 1)
  - Fragment, 1930; MS007.001.001.00230; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 083. Annotated: "First poem Jon ever wrote" Published in Tuftonian n s, 5:28, November 1930. The date has been estimated
  - Dusk, 1923; MS007.001.001.00231; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 084. Published in Glimpses: A National Anthology of Secondary School Verse, 1923 (Middleboro, MA: n p, 1923) p. 34. The date has been estimated
  - The skylark's flight, MS007.001.001.00232; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 084.
  - The old chief, 1923-10-28; MS007.001.001.00233; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 087.
  - Sudden pity, 1923-10-28; MS007.001.001.00234; Holmes, John (Box 1)
  - To a young man cleaning a motor-car, 1923-10-28; MS007.001.001.00235; Holmes, John (Box 1)
  - Labor, 1923-10-28; MS007.001.001.00236; Holmes, John (Box 1)
  - An old friend, 1923-11-12; MS007.001.001.00237; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 088.
  - Fragment from an old dance, 1923-11-12; MS007.001.001.00238; Holmes, John (Box 1)
  - A parting of the way, 1923-11-12; MS007.001.001.00239; Holmes, John (Box 1)
  - Song of my elf, MS007.001.001.00240; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 089.
  - Moon to a vagabond child, MS007.001.001.00241; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 090. Revision located 6:015 is entitled: Lullaby to a Vagabond Child revision in 6:015
  - The violinist, MS007.001.001.00242; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 090. revision in 8:119
  - A toast, MS007.001.001.00243; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 090.
  - Dream places, MS007.001.001.00244; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 091.
  - The second-hand bookshop, MS007.001.001.00245; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 092. Annotated
  - The fireplace, MS007.001.001.00246; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 092.
  - The breeze, MS007.001.001.00247; Holmes, John (Box 1)
  - The seeker, MS007.001.001.00248; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 093.
  - The market, 1923-06-25; MS007.001.001.00249; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 094.
  - The world, the world..., MS007.001.001.00250; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 095. duplicate in 5:47
  - Trees, 1924-06-01; MS007.001.001.00251; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 096.
  - You asked, 1924-06-01; MS007.001.001.00252; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 097.
  - Excuse, 1924-06-01; MS007.001.001.00253; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 097. Annotated
  - Ideals, MS007.001.001.00254; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 054. revision in 9:026
  - Recapture, 1924-06-01; MS007.001.001.00255; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 098.
  - Ask me not now, 1924-06-01; MS007.001.001.00256; Holmes, John (Box 1)
  - Youth goes forth, 1924; MS007.001.001.00257; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 099. Published: Somerville Herald, June 18, 1924; Class poem, read at high school graduation
  - Peace, 1924-06-01; MS007.001.001.00258; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 100.
  - Outburst, 1924-06-01; MS007.001.001.00259; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 100. Annotated
  - Prayer against blindness, 1924-07-01; MS007.001.001.00260; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 101. Revision in 7:103 is annotated. revision in 7:103
  - A memory, 1924-07-01; MS007.001.001.00261; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 101. Duplicate in 7:103 is annotated. Annotated duplicate in 7:103
  - Who has not known, 1924-07-01; MS007.001.001.00262; Holmes, John (Box 1)
  - The pure of heart, 1924-07-01; MS007.001.001.00263; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 102. Annotated duplicate in 7:103
  - A life, 1924-07-01; MS007.001.001.00264; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 102.
  - At camp-fire, 1924-07-01; MS007.001.001.00265; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 102. Revision in 7:105 is annotated. Revision in 11:004 is titled: "Woodcraft circle" duplicate in 5:105, revisions in 7:105 and 11:004
  - Book-reading, 1924-07-01; MS007.001.001.00266; Holmes, John (Box 1)
  - The end of day, 1924-07-01; MS007.001.001.00267; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 103. revision in 8:056
  - In the arbor, 1924-07-01; MS007.001.001.00268; Holmes, John (Box 1)
  - A fireplace in December, 1924-07-01; MS007.001.001.00269; Holmes, John (Box 1)
  - Poems on pictures, 1924-07-01; MS007.001.001.00270; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 104. Revision in 7:101 is annotated. duplicate in 1:109, revision in 7:101
  - Laus perennis, 1924-07-01; MS007.001.001.00271; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 104. Annotated
  - Steps, 1924-07-01; MS007.001.001.00272; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 105. duplicate in 9:048
  - The angel of love, 1924-07-01; MS007.001.001.00273; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 105. Revision in 9:048 is annotated. revision in 9:048
  - Matinata, 1924-07-01; MS007.001.001.00274; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 106.
  - To a player at the Globe, 1924-07-01; MS007.001.001.00275; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 106. minor revisions in 1:109
  - A portrait [My sister], 1924-07-01; MS007.001.001.00276; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 106. Revision in 1:127 titled "My sister". Duplicate in 10:034, p. 103 is handwritten. revision, March 1925, 1:127 and duplicate in 10:034, p. 103
  - An old poet, 1924-07-01; MS007.001.001.00277; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 107.
  - Pageant, 1924-07-01; MS007.001.001.00278; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 108. Revision in 7:105 is annotated. revision in 7:105
  - Ruin, 1924-07-01; MS007.001.001.00279; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 108.
  - From a hollow in the woods, MS007.001.001.00280; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 110.
  - Twenty, MS007.001.001.00281; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 110. Duplicate in 9:064 is handwritten. duplicate in 9:064
  - October dusk, MS007.001.001.00282; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 110. Revision in 9:064 is handwritten. revision in 9:064
  - Life, MS007.001.001.00283; Holmes, John (Box 1)
  - Direction, MS007.001.001.00284; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 111. duplicate in 10:034, p. 95
  - The shining road, MS007.001.001.00285; Holmes, John (Box 1)
  - Old music, MS007.001.001.00286; Holmes, John (Box 1)
  - Song to be said to my pillow, MS007.001.001.00287; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 111.
  - Sounds, MS007.001.001.00288; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 112. revision in 7:122
  - If ever, MS007.001.001.00289; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 113.
  - Fragment, MS007.001.001.00290; Holmes, John (Box 1)
  - A door, MS007.001.001.00291; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 113. Annotated
  - After, MS007.001.001.00292; Holmes, John (Box 1)
  - Relief, MS007.001.001.00293; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 114. Revision 7:119
  - Passing, MS007.001.001.00294; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 114.
  - Trees in the wind, MS007.001.001.00295; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 114. revision in 7:119
  - Candles, MS007.001.001.00296; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 114. Annotated; Revision in 7:119 revision in 7:119
  - Weary, 1924-12-01; MS007.001.001.00297; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 115. Revision located 4:42 annotated: "These three ["Keys", "Money", and "Weary"] are going to be published in Palms, in the fall. I had to change the last of Weary of the them- in case you remember a different ending about "hearing a bell", to ... with "going back down the Hill again to Hill." Revision in 10:034, p. 102 is handwritten. Published in Palms, 4:83, December 1926. Presented for the Irene Glascock Memorial Prize Reading at Mt. Holyoke College, May 7, 1926. Published: Palms, December 1926 duplicate in 2:27, revision in 4:29; 4:42; 10:010, p. 9; 10:034, p. 49; 10:034, p.102; 10:035, p. 121; duplicate of revision in 2:027
  - The fog, 1924-12-01; MS007.001.001.00298; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 115. revision in 7:080
  - The puddle, 1924-12-01; MS007.001.001.00299; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 115.
  - [Mood] Workman, MS007.001.001.00300; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 116. Revision in folder 2:19 presented at the Irene Glascock Memorial Prize Reading at Mt. Holyoke College, May 7, 1926. Revision in 7:030 is annotated. revisions in 2:19 and 7:030
  - Conrad has an evening, 1924-12-25; MS007.001.001.00301; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 117. Annotated revision in 8:048
  - The child on the other shore, 1924-12-25; MS007.001.001.00302; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 118. Duplicate in 10:034, p. 90 is handwritten duplicate in 10:034, p. 90
  - Song, 1924-12-25; MS007.001.001.00303; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 118.
  - A pale lady looks in a deep well, 1924-12-25; MS007.001.001.00304; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 118. duplicate in 7:080
  - A life, 1925-02-26; MS007.001.001.00305; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 119. Annotated revision in 9:039
  - Poetry and music [Poem] [A poem can tell], 1925-02-26; MS007.001.001.00306; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 119. Annotated; revision in 2:96 entitled "Poem". Revision in 10:034, p. 95 is crossed out. revisions, March 1925, 1:126; 2:96; 10:010, p. 9; 10:034, p. 62; 10:034, p. 95; 10:035, p. 121
  - For the grave of unknown citizens, 1925-02-27; MS007.001.001.00307; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 120.
  - To himself, 1925-02-27; MS007.001.001.00308; Holmes, John (Box 1)
  - The coward, 1925-02-27; MS007.001.001.00309; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 120. Annotated
  - [Moment macabre: symphony] Moment grotesque: symphony, 1925-02-01; MS007.001.001.00310; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 121. Revision in folder 2:21 presented for the Irene Glascock Memorial Prize Reading at Mt. Holyoke College, May 7, 1926. Revision in 7:032 is annotated. revisions in 2:21, 7:032 and duplicate in 1:121
  - Midnight, 1925-02-01; MS007.001.001.00311; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 121.
  - Girl with a Spanish shawl (a picture), 1925-02-01; MS007.001.001.00312; Holmes, John (Box 1)
  - Conrad sleeping, 1925-02-01; MS007.001.001.00313; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 122. Annotated
  - Tell me why, 1925-02-01; MS007.001.001.00314; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 122.
  - Questioning, 1925-03-01; MS007.001.001.00315; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 123.
  - An inscription, 1925-03-01; MS007.001.001.00316; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 124.
  - An old, old man, 1925-03-01; MS007.001.001.00317; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 124. Revision in 9:065 is titled: Old, old man. revision in 9:065
  - Rather than this, 1925-03-01; MS007.001.001.00318; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 125. Annotated Presented for the Irene Glascock Memorial Prize Reading at Mt. Holyoke College, May 7, 1926. duplicate in 2:26
  - If this were the last, 1925-03-01; MS007.001.001.00319; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 126. Duplicate in 10:034, p. 93 is handwritten revision in 9:039 and duplicate in 10:034, p. 93
  - Portrait [His World], 1925-03-01; MS007.001.001.00320; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 127.
  - A letter in March, 1925-03-01; MS007.001.001.00321; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 128. Annotated: "Robert Frost-like but no good"
  - Rocks, 1925-04-15; MS007.001.001.00322; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 129.
  - Your head, 1925-04-15; MS007.001.001.00323; Holmes, John (Box 1)
  - Money, 1925-04-15; MS007.001.001.00324; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 129. Annotated; Duplicate located 4:42 annotated: "These three ["Keys", "Money", and "Weary"] are going to be published in Palms, in the fall. I had to change the last of Weary of the them- in case you remember a different ending about "hearing a bell", to ... with "going back down the Hill again to Hill."- Published in Palms, 4:82, December 1926. Duplicate in 2:25 presented for the Irene Glascock Memorial Prize Reading at Mt. Holyoke College, May 7, 1926. duplicates in 2:25 and 4:42
  - The old man and the moon, 1925-04-15; MS007.001.001.00325; Holmes, John (Box 1)
  - The flaming lights, 1925-04-08; MS007.001.001.00326; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 130. Annotated. Duplicate in 1:130 dated April 24, 1925. duplicate, April 24, 1925, 1:1
  - Home, 1925-04-08; MS007.001.001.00327; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 130. Revision in 10:034, p. 94 is handwritten revision in 10:034, p. 94
  - The long watch, 1925-04-03; MS007.001.002.00328; Holmes, John (Box 2)
    Box 2 folder 001. Annotated
  - On quiet hill, 1925-04-03; MS007.001.002.00329; Holmes, John (Box 2)
    Box 2 folder 002.
  - Consideration of a friend, 1925-04-03; MS007.001.002.00330; Holmes, John (Box 2)
  - Song, 1925-04-03; MS007.001.002.00331; Holmes, John (Box 2)
    Box 2 folder 002. Annotated
  - Price of wisdom, 1925; MS007.001.002.00332; Holmes, John (Box 2)
    Box 2 folder 003.
  - Consecrate, 1925; MS007.001.002.00333; Holmes, John (Box 2)
  - Jingle verse: The Boston Wanderlust, 1925; MS007.001.002.00334; Holmes, John (Box 2)
    Box 2 folder 004.
  - A sailor's R.I.P., 1925; MS007.001.002.00335; Holmes, John (Box 2)
    Box 2 folder 004. Annotated
  - Turn from the fire, 1925; MS007.001.002.00336; Holmes, John (Box 2)
  - Ballad of an ordinary man, 1925; MS007.001.002.00337; Holmes, John (Box 2)
    Box 2 folder 005. Annotated
  - What might have been, 1925; MS007.001.002.00338; Holmes, John (Box 2)
    Box 2 folder 006. Annotated
  - Ease after pain, 1925; MS007.001.002.00339; Holmes, John (Box 2)
  - An April afternoon, 1925; MS007.001.002.00340; Holmes, John (Box 2)
    Box 2 folder 006. duplicate in 8:025
  - Stone and roots, Spring, 1925; MS007.001.002.00341; Holmes, John (Box 2)
    Box 2 folder 007.
  - To Peter, who is not a real person, 1925; MS007.001.002.00342; Holmes, John (Box 2)
    Box 2 folder 008. duplicate in 2:008 and revision in 10:034, p. 112. Spring 1925
  - Two sonnets on death and immortal man [The cold shadow], 1925; MS007.001.002.00343; Holmes, John (Box 2)
    Box 2 folder 009. Annotated/ Duplicate is annotated and entitled: The cold shadow duplicate in 8:047
  - To a girl I know, 1925-05-01; MS007.001.002.00344; Holmes, John (Box 2)
    Box 2 folder 010.
  - My enemy, 1925-05-01; MS007.001.002.00345; Holmes, John (Box 2)
  - On the new moon, 1925-06-23; MS007.001.002.00346; Holmes, John (Box 2)
    Box 2 folder 011. Annotated. Revision in 10:035, p. 166 is titled: New moon rising. duplicate in 2:011 and revision in 10:035, p. 166
  - Mowing, 1925-07-01; MS007.001.002.00347; Holmes, John (Box 2)
    Box 2 folder 012. Annotated. Revision in 9:050 is annotated. revision in 9:050
  - The shore, 1925-07-01; MS007.001.002.00348; Holmes, John (Box 2)
    Box 2 folder 013. Duplicate in 2:013 is annotated. Revision in 9:080 is dated: June 1925 duplicate in 2:013 and revision in 9:080
  - Wind in the night, 1925-09-01; MS007.001.002.00349; Holmes, John (Box 2)
    Box 2 folder 014. revision in 9:009 and duplicate in 2:014
  - Quickening, 1925; MS007.001.002.00350; Holmes, John (Box 2)
    Box 2 folder 015. Duplicate in 2:015 is titled: Splendid and Terrible duplicate in 2:015
  - On awakening suddenly, 1925-12-01; MS007.001.002.00351; Holmes, John (Box 2)
    Box 2 folder 016.
  - To the easily forgotten, 1925-12-01; MS007.001.002.00352; Holmes, John (Box 2)
  - On seeing the title "Heart of darkness", 1925-12-01; MS007.001.002.00353; Holmes, John (Box 2)
  - The marchers in the shadow, 1925-12-01; MS007.001.002.00354; Holmes, John (Box 2)
    Box 2 folder 017. revision in 7:016
  - Poem, 1925-12-01; MS007.001.002.00355; Holmes, John (Box 2)
    Box 2 folder 017.
  - The hour, 1925-12-01; MS007.001.002.00356; Holmes, John (Box 2)
  - Peter has an evening, 1926; MS007.001.002.00357; Holmes, John (Box 2)
    Box 2 folder 018. Revision in 5:058 is annotated Published in Lyric, 8:3, August 1928; Tufts Weekly, October 29 1925, p. 5. Presented for the Irene Glascock Memorial Prize Reading, Mt. Holyoke College, May 7, 1926. revision in 5:058 and duplicates in 2:18 and 3:075
  - Sonnet, 1926; MS007.001.002.00358; Holmes, John (Box 2)
    Box 2 folder 020. Presented for the Irene Glascock Memorial Prize Reading, Mt. Holyoke College, May 7, 1926. duplicate in 2:020
  - Tower of glass, 1926; MS007.001.002.00359; Holmes, John (Box 2)
    Box 2 folder 022. Presented for the Irene Glascock Memorial Prize Reading, Mt. Holyoke College, May 7, 1926. duplicate in 2:022 and revision in 8:099
  - My attic room, 1926; MS007.001.002.00360; Holmes, John (Box 2)
    Box 2 folder 023. Published in Tuftonian n s, 1:22, May 1926. Presented for the Irene Glascock Memorial Prize Reading at Mt. Holyoke College, May 7, 1926. revision in 3:57 and duplicate in 2:023
  - Tir na n'og, 1926; MS007.001.002.00361; Holmes, John (Box 2)
    Box 2 folder 024. Presented for the Irene Glascock Memorial Prize Reading at Mt. Holyoke College, May 7, 1926. duplicate in 2:024
  - Keys, 1926; MS007.001.002.00362; Holmes, John (Box 2)